Riyadh Tamish Sana'a City, Yemen riyadh.tamish@gmail.com (+967) 772325333 (+967) 716000602



PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a senior teacher, lecturer and trainer in the fields of:

- Business Administration for 1 year
- English for academic, personal, institutional and business purposes for 15 years' experience.
- Islamic culture in both Arabic and English for 8 years.
- Computer (Introduction to Computer, Microsoft Office) for 1 year.
- Physics in English (Cambridge and Oxford Curriculum) for 6 months.

I am a highly organized manager with 6 years' experience, I had successfully managed admin skills to possess strong interpersonal skills, recruit, train, supervise, monitor and evaluate staff and teachers, lay off, improve working environment and commitment to employee welfare, familiar with the payroll system and the employment law, coordinate schedules, prepare budget and estimate cost, make reports and recommendations, identify rules and regulations, solve problems and make decisions, structure compensation and bonus, conduct performance and satisfaction surveys, plan and manage projects, formulate and implement strategies. Looking to leverage my knowledge, skills and experience into a role as administrative or teaching position.

EDUCATION

2017 - 2021 International University of Technology Twintech (IUTT)

Sana'a, Yemen

Master of Business Administration (MBA)

- MBA Thesis Title "Factors affecting students' choice for private universities in Yemen"
- Researches, questionnaires, evaluation and reports, case studies and presentations, projects, study and analysis of all MBA subjects etc...
- Programs such as VISO & Arena in Operation Management, MS Project in Project Management & SPSS in Business Research Methods
- Excellent Degree (First Class Honor with a GPA 3.84)

2021 SANA'A UNIVERSITY

Sana'a, Yemen

Certificate of Proficiency in English Language

• Excellent degree

2005 - 2009 SANA'A UNIVERSITY

Sana'a, Yemen

Bachelor of Arts and Humanities, English Literature

Very good degree

2005 - 2009 FACULTY OF ARTS AND HUMANITIES

Sana'a, Yemen

Alison ABC IT (1-2-3) and Alison Touch Typing Skills (online)

• Excellent Degree

2008 SANA'A UNIVERSITY, COMPUTER CENTER

Sana'a, Yemen

Sana'a University Computer Driving License

• Excellent Degree

Secretarial Diploma

• Very Good Degree

EXPERIENCE

2017-Present International University of Technology Twintech (IUTT)

Sana'a, Yemen

A Member of IUTT Senate (University Council)

- Make and approve the rules and the regulations
- Make decision, policies and solve problems
- Create, implement and evaluate strategies
- Coordinate, control and monitor the work process
- Discuss academic and work issues

2017-Present International University of Technology Twintech (IUTT)

Sana'a, Yemen

Head of Common (Requirement) Subjects & English Language Center Manager

- Recruit, induct and train staff and teachers
- Supervise, monitor and evaluate staff and teachers
- Conduct performance and satisfaction surveys
- Improve working environment and commitment to employee welfare
- Plan and manage projects
- Formulate and implement strategies
- Coordinate schedules, prepare budget and estimate cost
- Make reports and recommendations, solve problems and make decisions
- Select textbooks and modify the curriculum and provide class materials
- Allocate students to lectures and assign lecturers to subjects
- Provide activities and tests
- Work, revise, check and manage students' coursework and final exams
- Interview the new applicants
- Conduct the placement test and group the accepted and weak students
- Revise, check and announce students' marks

2021-Present International University of Technology Twintech (IUTT)

Sana'a, Yemen

A business Administration Lecturer

- Currently teaching the following subjects
- Strategic Management Macroeconomics
- Principles of Marketing International Marketing
- Able to teach the following subjects
- Operation Management Project Management International Management
- Marketing Management Principles of Management Quality Management
- Business Communication Organizational Behavior International Business
- Entrepreneurship Business Research Methods
- Deliver scheduled lectures in an efficient way with professional and modern techniques
- Arrange tests, assignments and presentations to evaluate students' performance

A business Administration Researches Supervisor

- "Strategies affecting work morale and productivity on Yemeni organizations"
- "Delaying tuition fees impact on universities' performance"

2013-Present International University of Technology Twintech (IUTT)

Sana'a, Yemen

An English Lecturer

- Teach English for academic listening, speaking, reading and writing skills with grammar
- Teach English for Specific Purposes at all faculties
- Teach Preparatory English Courses to IUTT candidates
- Deliver scheduled lectures in an efficient way with professional and modern techniques
- Arranged tests, assignments and presentations to evaluate students' performance

2013 - 2021 International University of Technology Twintech (IUTT)

Sana'a, Yemen

An Islamic Lecturer

- Teach Islamic Culture course in English with Islamic English Terms.
- Discuss scientific miracles in the Holy Quran and Sunnah.
- Deliver scheduled lectures in an efficient way with professional and modern techniques
- Arrange tests, assignments and presentations to evaluate students' performance

2019-2021 AL-HABISHI AND HIS PARTNERS FOR TRADE

Alwadia'a, Hadramoat, Yemen

A General Manger & Accountant manager

- Manage all the operational requirements of the supermarket
- Deal with all customers' complaints & recognize their requirements
- Recruit staff, organize training, assign tasks, appraise, monitor, and plan tasks
- Review merchandising by formulating pricing policies
- Increase sales and determine all required sales promotions towards marketing
- Improve profit and identify profitability ratio by studying financial and operating statements
- Schedule expenditure, prepare annual budget and achieve financial objectives
- Maintain inventories and approve contracts to ensure consistent availability of the required services and merchandise
- Ensure all manual documents relating to sales are correctly posted into the system in the correct accounting period
- Input and update product-costing formulations in the system for new items.
- Ensure accurate posting, valuation and reconciliation to stock ledger/general ledger
- Prepare and use accounting software (Betasys, mini express accounting system)

2020 PEACE AND SECURITY ORGANIZATION

Sana'a, Yemen

(Volunteer) Community Engagement and Women Empowerment

- Capacity building training in women project management
- English skills and correspondence
- Preparing CV and a cover letter

2016-2017 MANARAT SANA'A SCHOOL

Sana'a, Yemen

A Senior English Teacher

- Taught English to grades 5, 6, 7 & 8 Macmillan & International English curriculum.
- Delivered scheduled classes in an efficient way with professional and modern techniques
- Arranged tests, assignments and presentations to evaluate students' performance

2016-2018 **PHARMACY WORLD**

Sana'a, Yemen

- Interpret to foreign staff
- Interpret meetings
- Translate documents and emails

2009-2014 CANADIAN CENTER FOR TRAINING & CAPACITY DEVELOPMENT

Sana'a, Yemen

A Senior English Teacher

- Taught English for TOFEL iBT, Local TOFEL, Diploma Program & Summer Courses.
- Taught English for Specific Purposes (British Embassy Employees, Government & Private Sectors)
- Delivered classes in an efficient way with professional and modern techniques
- Arranged tests, assignments and presentations to evaluate students' performance

2010-2013 SABAFON COMPANY (TELECOMMUNICATION COMPANY)

Sana'a, Yemen

A Customer Care Agent

- Answer incoming calls and respond to customer's complains
- Possess strong and affective interpersonal skills to deal with customers and staff
- Research, identify, and resolve customer complaints using applicable software
- Recognize, document, and alert the management team of trends in customer calls
- Follow up customer calls where necessary

2010-2012 **DAR-ALSLAM ORGANIZATION**

Sana'a, Yemen

An Interpreter and a Translator

- Interpret to foreign staff
- Interpret meetings
- Translate documents and emails

2009 AZAL INSTITUTE

Sana'a, Yemen

An English coordinator and teacher

- Select textbooks and provide class materials
- Supervise, monitor and evaluate staff and teachers
- Allocate students to classes and assign teachers to classes
- Provide activities and tests
- Taught English for Diploma Program & Summer Courses

AMERICAN ACADEMY FOR TRAINING 2008 - 2009

Sana'a, Yemen

An English teacher

- Taught English for Diploma Program & Summer Courses
- Arranged tests, assignments and presentations to evaluate students' performance

2008 NATIONAL AMERICAN INSTITUTE

Sana'a, Yemen

A Computer Teacher

- Design, facilitate, and teach the computer instruction component
- Taught basic computer knowledge of software and MS Office
- Prepare execute lesson plans, assigning tasks, and evaluating student work and progress

TRAINING

CANADIAN CENTER FOR TRAINING & CAPACITY DEVELOPMENT

Sana'a, Yemen

2012, Sep 6th to 28th Teaching Knowledge Test (TKT), British Council

2010, July 8th to 30th Pronunciation, British Council

SABAFON COMPANY (TELECOMMUNICATION COMPANY)

Sana'a, Yemen

2010, Mar 6th to 31th Oracle & Technical Programs

INTERNATIONAL UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY TWINTECH (IUTT)

Sana'a, Yemen

2014, June 15th Module Implementing Plan for curriculum

2014, June 16th & 17th Course Specification

2018, Jan 10th & 11th Learning Management System (LMS)

2018, May 13th & 14th
2021, Apr 26th & 27th
Design programs based on learning outcomes, vision, mission, goals and outcomes
Administrative and organizational development and job performance improvement

AL-HABISHI AND HIS PARTNERS FOR TRADE

Sana'a, Yemen

2019, May 22nd to 24th Betasys, mini express accounting system

SKILLS AND ACTIVITIES

- Excellent Microsoft Office skills, network, internet, install and format
- English and Arabic typing 30 WPM
- Excellent Fluency in English and Arabic
- Excellent communication skills, self-motivated and highly optimist and enthusiast
- Ability to work efficiently within a team or individually
- Knowledge and experience of intercultural differences

REFERNCES

Prof. Wael Al-Aghbari President of IUTT Wael.Aghbari@gmail.com +967 777869168

Prof. Mogeeb Mosleh, Vice President of IUTT for Academic Affairs MogeebMosleh@gmail.com +967 778448888

Dr. Aqeel Alsurmi, Vice President of IUTT for Students Affairs aqeelalsurmi@gmail.com +967 775 0300 886

Dr. Emad Al-Rmada, Dean of Business & Finance at IUTT <u>dr_emadnuman@yahoo.com</u> +967 773 172 475

Prof. Moahmmed Al-Awlaqi, Dean of Graduate Studies at LIU (Lebanese International University) mohammed.awlaqi@ye.liu.edu.ib +967 777 195 232

Prof. Ahmed Al-Hadramy, Strategic Management Professor, Sana'a University dhadramy@gmail.com +967 777 901 962

Dr. Aref Alhaj, Accounting Professor, Sana'a University & IUTT University and a consultant for GC-USA AID/UN Women aref262@gmial.com

+967 770 669 037